Cheryl Crawford Collection
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Cheryl Crawford Collection
1862-1981
Crawford, Cheryl
Cheryl Crawford worked as a theatre producer for five decades, primarily on Broadway, producing musicals that included Brigadoon, Porgy and Bess, and Yentl, and four Tennessee Williams plays. She was also a founding member of both the Group Theatre and the Actors Studio. Her collection includes correspondence, production materials, scripts, programs, playbills, audio tapes, posters, and sound recordings, as well as her personal collection of sheet music.
25 boxes; 11.4 linear feet
1978-002
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Biographical Note
Producer and director Cheryl Crawford was born Sept. 24, 1902 in Akron, Ohio to Louella E. (Parker) and Robert K. Crawford. Crawford died on Oct. 7, 1986 in New York City.
Although involved in at least one high school dramatic production, Crawford began her formal acting career while at Smith College, when she became involved with Smith College Dramatic Association. While a student, she produced Shakuntala, a Native American drama. During the summer of 1924 Crawford was associated with the Provincetown Players of Cape Cod. In 1925 she graduated from Smith College, cum laude.
Following graduation, Crawford attended a school managed by the Theatre Guild in New York City. She worked with the Theatre Guild until 1930, working first as a secretary and a third assistant manager. Later she worked as a casting director and general assistant on Theatre Guild productions.
In 1930 Crawford left the Theatre Guild to form the Group Theatre, sharing the responsibilities as director of the group with Harold Clurman and Lee Strasberg. During this period she directed Big Night (1933), Till the Day I Die (1935), and Weep for the Virgins (1935) as well as assisting with the direction of the first production by the Group Theatre, The House of Connelly (1931). She left the Group Theatre in 1937 to begin directing on her own.
Between 1937 and her death in 1986 Crawford was involved in the production of more than 100 shows. From 1937 through 1945 Crawford worked primarily on Broadway. While working at the Maplewood Theatre in New Jersey, 1940-1942, she produced different shows on a weekly basis and worked with such stars as Tallulah Bankhead, Ingrid Bergman, Gloria Swanson in productions such as The Time of Your Life and Charley's Aunt.
In 1946 Crawford formed the American Repertory Theatre with Eva Le Gallienne and Margaret Webster. In 1947 Crawford united with Robert Lewis and Elia Kazan to form the Actors Studio. Crawford served as both a member of the board of directors and as an executive producer during the Actors Studio Theatre, which ran during 1963 and 1964.
Crawford was active as a producer for fifty-five years, co-producing So Long on Lonely Street in 1986. During that time she produced musicals such as Brigadoon, Porgy and Bess, Paint Your Wagon, and Celebration. Crawford also produced four Tennessee Williams plays, among them Sweet Bird of Youth, in which Paul Newman starred, and Period of Adjustment. Some of the highlights from productions during the last decades of her life include Yentl, Mother Courage and Her Children, and Do You Turn Somersaults.
Crawford's awards include an honorary Doctor of Literature from Smith College, awarded in 1962, and an Antoinette Perry (Tony) Award in 1951 for Tennessee William's The Rose Tattoo. She was named Woman of the Year in 1959. In 1964 she was awarded an Achievement Medal from Brandeis University.
Source
Notable Women in the American Theatre: A Biographical Dictionary. New York, New York: Greenwood Press, 1989. 173-176.
Scope and Contents
The Cheryl Crawford Collection documents her career in theatre from almost the beginning through the years immediately preceding the sale of her collection to the University of Houston. Items date between 1862 and 1981, with the bulk of the items dated 1940 through 1978. There are 3,335 items in the collection.
The collection includes correspondence, production materials, scripts, programs, playbills, audio tapes, posters, sheet music, sound recordings, clippings, budgets, tax returns, legal agreements, contracts, audits, reviews, speeches, and miscellaneous items such as postcards and receipts.
The series are arranged as follows: Correspondence, Productions, Scripts, Programs, Playbills, Serials, Audio Tapes, Sheet Music, Sound Recordings, a General series for miscellaneous items, and Posters. The finding aid includes a complete container listing. Item listings of correspondence, production materials, playbills, programs, and general items are available upon request.
Some printed items have been removed from the collection and incorporated into the library's cataloged holdings. These materials include books and some sheet music. The materials which have been removed from the collection and cataloged are available for use.
Subjects (Persons)
Crawford, Cheryl, 1902-1986; Kazan, Elia; Martin, Mary, 1913-; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975; Williams, Tennessee, 1911-1983
Subjects (Organizations)
Group Theatre (U.S.); Actors Studio (New York, N.Y.)
Subjects
Theatrical producers and directors -- United States
Access Restrictions
Open for research.
Acquisition
The collection was purchased from Cheryl Crawford in 1978.
Detailed Description
- Correspondence, 1936-1977
  There are 438 items in this series. The correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Letters received and sent have been kept together, as that is the arrangement used by Crawford. Letters date from 1936 to 1977, with the bulk of the material dated 1950 through 1961.
  In some cases, the only correspondence with a particular person are the carbon copies saved by Crawford. People to which carbon copies of letters sent are all that were kept are: Judy Garland, Oscar Hammerstein, Burgess Meredith, Marilyn Monroe, Shelley Winters, and Audrey Wood. Major correspondents include Mary Martin and Richard Halliday, Marc Blitzstein, Tennessee Williams, and Thornton Wilder. A complete listing of letters sent and received is available.
  This series does not include correspondence related to specific productions which has been filed with other materials related to that production. Additional correspondence related to a particular production is located with other records of the production. There also is some correspondence in the General series, placed with related items such as the Diary of Anne Frank lawsuit file.
  There is little personal correspondence, as most items relate directly to activities in the theatre.
  - Letter from Jane Alexander, 1976.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter from Judith Alexander, undated.; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Telegram from James Baldwin, 1964.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter from Tallulah Bankhead to Kieran Tunney, 1965.; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters from Vicki Baum, telegram and carbon copies of letters to Vicki Baum, additional materials, 1944.; 12 items (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters from Vicki Baum, telegram and carbon copies of letters to Vicki Baum, additional materials, 1944-1945.; 11 items (Box 1, Folder 5a)
  - Letters from Marc Blitzstein, carbon copies of letters to Marc Blitzstein, additional materials, 1949-1960.; 35 items (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter from Marlon Brando, 1953.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letter from Bertoldt Brecht to Roth, additional item, 1950.; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letter from Gower Champion, 1968.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letter from Paddy Chayefsky, 1961.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Agnes de Mille, 1976.; 3 item (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - David Diamond, undated.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letters from Lehman Engel, carbon copies of letters to Lehman Engel, 1965-1967.; 27 items (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Letters from Lynn Fontanne, 1975.; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Carbon copies of letters to Pamela Frankau, 1955.; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Carbon copies of letters to Judy Garland, 1961.; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letter from Paul Green, 1975.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Carbon copies of letters to Oscar Hammerstein, 1954-1955.; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letters from Julie Harris, 1974-1976.; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Letters from Helen Hayes, 1973-1974.; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Letter from Elia Kazan, carbon copies of letters to Elia Kazan, additional materials., 1950-1957.; 20 items (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Letters from Elia Kazan, letter from Elia Kazan to Lee Strasberg, carbon copies of letters to Elia Kazan, additional materials, 1958-1975.; 43 items (Box 1, Folder 21a)
  - Letters from Ephraim Kishon, carbon copies of letters to Ephraim Kishon, 1961.; 6 items (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Letter from Eva La Gallienne, undated.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Letter from Cloris Leachman, 1977.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Letter from Lotta Lenya, 1976.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Letters from Alan Lerner, carbon copies of letters to Alan Lerner, 1951.; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Letters from Carson McCullers, letter from Carson McCullers to Otto Frank, carbon copies of letters to Carson McCullers, additional materials, 1952-1961.; 11 items (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Letter from Anna Magnani (photocopy), 1962.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Letters from Mary Martin and Richard Halliday, carbon copies of letters to Mary Martin and Richard Halliday, additional materials, 1945-1963.; 53 items (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Letters from Mary Martin and Richard Halliday, additional materials, 1972-1977.; 13 items (Box 1, Folder 29a)
  - Carbon copy of letter to Burgess Meredith, 1964.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Carbon copies of letters to Marilyn Monroe, 1955-1961.; 7 items (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Letter from Michael Moriarty, 1974.; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Carbon copy of letter to Henry Lee Munson, 1960.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Letter from Paul Newman, carbon copies of letters to Paul Newman, 1960-1962.; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Carbon copy of letter to Mike Nichols and Elaine May, 1961.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Letters from Clifford Odets, carbon copies of letters to Clifford Odets, 1936-1961.; 6 items (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Letters from Laurence Olivier, carbon copies of letters to Laurence Olivier, 1953-1977.; 5 items (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Letter from Alan J. Pakula, 1959.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Letters to Lynn Riggs (photocopies), 1936.; 8 items (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Letter from Samantha Rowe Rau, 1958.; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Carbon copies of letters to Lee Strasberg, card from Lee Strasberg, 1961-1963.; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Letter from Franchot Tone, 1953.; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Letter from Eli Wallach, 1954.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Carbon copy of letter to Robert Wallston, 1961.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Letter from Margaret Webster, 1937-1972.; 11 items (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Letter from Helen Weigel (photocopy), 1968.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Letter from Kurt Weill, 1937.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Letter from Orson Welles, telegram and carbon copies of letters to Orson Welles, additional materials, 1960-1961.; 10 items (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Letters from Thornton Wilder, carbon copies of letters to Thornton and Isobel Wilder, 1946-1975.; 24 items (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Letters and photocopies of letters from Tennessee Williams, carbon copies of letters to Tennessee Williams, 1948-1954.; 29 items (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Letters and photocopies of letters from Tennessee Williams, carbon copies of letters to Tennessee Williams, 1956-1976.; 27 items (Box 1, Folder 50a)
  - Carbon copy of letter to Shelley Winters, 1967.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Carbon copies of letters to Audrey Wood, 1948-1953.; 6 items (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Carbon copies of letters to Ceciley Youmans and John Patrick, additional materials, 1954-1955.; 22 items (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Productions, 1938-1976
  Production materials are arranged alphabetically by the title of the production. Within each production, materials are arranged chronologically, although in some cases where the amount of material warrants separation the materials are divided by category (i.e. legal, financial, etc.). The materials are dated 1938 to 1976, with the bulk of the materials dated 1944 through 1976. There are 2,060 items in this series.
  Materials include legal agreements, contracts, financial records, insurance policies, costume descriptions, receipts, box office statements, and correspondence related to the productions.
  - Alice in Wonderland, 1947.; 8 items (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - All the Living, 1938.; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Another Sun, 1940.; 30 items (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Big Hello, 1961-1962.; 34 items (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Brigadoon, 1948-1951.; 8 items (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The Closing Door, 1949-1950.; 14 items (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Camille, 1961-1962.; 39 items (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Camille, 1962.; 21 items (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Camille, 1962.; 23 items (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Celebration. Broker Sales, 1969.; 16 items (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Celebration. Cash/Costumes, 1968-1969.; 173 items (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Celebration. Cash/Misc, 1968-1969.; 65 items (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Celebration. Cash/Props, 1968-1969.; 151 items (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Celebration. Financial Records, 1968-1969.; 17 items (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Celebration. Financial Records by Week, 1969.; 23 items (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Celebration. Financial Records by Week, 1969.; 12 items (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Celebration. Financial Records by Week, 1969.; 11 items (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Celebration. Financial Records by Week, 1969.; 20 items (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Celebration. Financial Records by Week, 1969.; 22 items (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Celebration. Financial Records by Week, 1969.; 19 items (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Celebration. Financial Records by Week, 1969.; 20 items (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Celebration. Financial Records by Week, 1969.; 20 items (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Celebration. Financial Records by Week, 1969.; 11 items (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Celebration. Financial Records by Week, 1969.; 17 items (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Celebration. Financial Records by Week, 1969.; 11 items (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - The Closing Door, 1949-1950.; 23 items (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Film of Memory, 1956-1957.; 41 items (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The Film of Memory, 1958-1967.; 58 items (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Flowers of Virtue, 1941.; 19 items (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The Flowers of Virtue, 1942.; 39 items (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The Flowers of Virtue, 1942.; 8 items (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Freaking Out of Stephanie Blake. Correspondence, 1967.; 47 items (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - The Freaking Out of Stephanie Blake. Correspondence, 1967.; 30 items (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - The Freaking Out of Stephanie Blake. Legal, 1967.; 22 items (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Happy End, 1963-1964.; 47 items (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Happy End, 1964-1965.; 44 items (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Hold Back the Dawn, 1958-1959.; 50 items (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Hold Back the Dawn, 1960-1961.; 71 items (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Hold Back the Dawn, 1961.; 16 items (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - The Honeys, 1955.; 41 items (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Jennie, 1963.; 51 items (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Judith Hearne, 1957-1958.; 12 items (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Love Life. Costumes, 1948-1949.; 24 items (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - The Love Suicide at Schofield Barracks, 1971-1972.; 20 items (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Mister Johnson, 1957-1963.; 13 items (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - New Person, 1966.; 7 items (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Peer Gynt, 1946-1951.; 70 items (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Perfect Marriage, 1944-1945.; 20 items (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Period of Adjustment, 1960-1961.; 19 items (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - The Rape of the Fair Country. Correspondence, 1965-1966.; 42 items (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - The Rape of the Fair Country. Expenses, 1965-1966.; 30 items (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - The Rape of the Fair Country. Legal, 1965-1966.; 11 items (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - The Rape of the Fair Country. Operating Budget, 1965-1966.; 8 items (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - The Rape of the Fair Country. Recordings, 1965-1966.; 7 items (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Regina, 1951.; 3 items (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Shadow of a Gunman, 1955-1959.; 44 items (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Shadow of a Gunman. Contracts, 1958.; 56 items (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Shadow of a Gunman. Financial Records, 1958.; 41 items (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Shadow of a Gunman. Production Records, 1958.; 23 items (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Yentl. Contracts, 1975.; 10 items (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Yentl. Correspondence, 1975-1976.; 10 items (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Yentl. Financing, 1975.; 3 items (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Yentl. Reviews, 1974-1975.; 41 items (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Yentl. Reviews, 1975.; 39 items (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Yentl. Reviews, 1975.; 16 items (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Yentl. Royalties, 1975-1976.; 34 items (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Yentl. Statements, 1975-1976.; 94 items (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Scripts, 1936-1970
  There are five full-length scripts in this series. They include two plays by Clifford Odets, The Nursery and Paradise Lost, the musical Johnny Johnson, written by Paul Green, Sweet Bird of Youth, written by Tennesee Williams, and The Trojan Women, written by F. G. Yerby.
  - Johnny Johnson, [1936].; 110 pages (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - The Nursery, 1953.; 30 pages (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Paradise Lost, undated.; 145 pages (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Sweet Bird of Youth, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - The Trojan Women, 1970.; 91 pages (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Programs, 1923-1978
  These materials date from 1923 through 1978, with the bulk of the material dated 1948 through 1978. There are 275 programs in this series.
  The programs have been separated into two sub-series; plays in which Crawford was involved in some fashion and plays in which she was not involved. Both sub-series are arranged alphabetically by title of the performance. Plays in which Crawford was not involved are further divided into American and British productions. The British programs include a few playbills produced in London for British productions.
  There are no programs in this series which date after 1951 for productions in which Crawford was involved. Those interested in programs for Crawford productions dated after 1951 should check the Playbills series.
  - Crawford, 1923-1951.; 32 items (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - A through D, 1935-1978.; 24 items (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - F through H, 1973-1978.; 11 items (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - J through P, 1940-1978.; 19 items (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - R through W, 1972-1978.; 22 items (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - British, A-Be, 1948-1971.; 17 items (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - British, Be-Co, 1948-1971.; 15 items (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - British, Co-Gi, 1948-1970.; 17 items (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - British, Gr-In, 1948-1970.; 13 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - British, Ir-Le, 1948-1973.; 12 items (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - British, Li-My, 1948-1973.; 18 items (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - British, Na-Qu, 1948-1977.; 15 items (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - British, R-Ro, 1958-1973.; 17 items (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - British, Ro-So, 1948-1970.; 13 items (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - British, Sq-Ti, 1958-1973.; 12 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - British, Ti-Wo, 1948-1973.; 18 items (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Playbills, 1939-1978.
  This series has been separated into two sub-series; playbills for productions in which Crawford was involved, and playbills for productions in which she was not involved. All items are arranged alphabetically by the title of the production. The bulk of the materials are dated 1973-1978. There are 123 items in this series.
  Playbills are commercially produced programs for theatrical productions, generally produced in larger cities with strong theatrical encalves such as New York and London. The playbills include features on various performers, articles on fashion, and other stories related to the theater and of interest to theatregoers.
  The playbills for non-Crawford productions have been separated American and miscellaneous productions. The collection includes 11 playbills for Crawford productions, including The Rose Tattoo, for which Crawford won a Tony Award.
  A complete listing of playbills is available upon request.
  - Crawford, 1939-1978.; 11 items (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - A-Ca, 1955-1977.; 13 items (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Ca-Da, 1955-1978.; 11 items (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Da-Ev, 1974-1978.; 11 items (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Fi-He, 1973-1978.; 16 items (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Hi-L, 1940-1978.; 13 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - M-Mu, 1940-1978.; 11 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - N-Ro, 1954-1978.; 14 items (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Ro-Th, 1954-1978.; 14 items (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Th-Wo, 1955-1975.; 9 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Serials, 1961-1984
  There are several serials relating to the stage which are included in Crawford's papers. The magazines are arranged chronologically. There are 12 items in this series, including several issues of Show Business Illustrated, one issue of Motion Picture, and one issue of Rona Barrett Looks At. The bulk of the material is dated 1961.
  - Show Business Illustrated, 1961.; 1 item (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Show Business Illustrated, 1961.; 1 item (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Show Business Illustrated, 1961.; 1 item (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Show Business Illustrated, 1961.; 1 item (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Show Business Illustrated, 1961.; 1 item (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Show Business Illustrated, 1961.; 1 item (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Show Business Illustrated, 1961.; 1 item (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Show Business Illustrated, 1962.; 1 item (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Show Business Illustrated, 1962.; 1 item (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Show Business Illustrated, 1962.; 1 item (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Motion Picture, 1974.; 1 item (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Rona Barrett Looks At., 1981.; 1 item (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Audiotapes, 1974
  This series has 8 items and includes interviews and recordings on audiotape. Included are two seven-inch reel-to-reel tapes; No For An Answer, and The Cradle Will Rock. There are also six three-inch reel-to-reel tapes and one cassette tape. The quality of these materials may vary. Only one tape has a date noted on the item.
  Please give the staff at least 24 hours advance notice if interested in using these materials in order to reserve equipment for the patron's use. The department is planning on transferring the reels to cassette tape for easier use by patrons.
  - Actors Studio (2 tapes). Cheryl Crawford on 3 inch reel, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Group Theatre Discussion. Harold Clurman and Cheryl Crawford on 3 inch reel, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Janet Flanner. Flanner discusses her life in Paris on cassette tape, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - No For An Answer. Marc Blitzstein on 7 inch reel, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - One Touch of Venus. Lotta Lenya discusses One Touch of Venus and Kurt Weill on 3 inch reel, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - One Touch of Venus. Agnes de Mille discusses One Touch of Venus on 3 inch reel, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - One Touch of Venus, Brigadoon. Cheryl Crawford on 3 inch reel, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - The Cradle Will Rock. Marc Blitzstein on 7 inch reel, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Sheet Music, 1862-1951
  The sheet music collection includes 128 items. The series has been arranged into two sub-series to separate the oversize items. Both sub-series are arranged alphabetically by title, with the oversize items following the standard items. The majority of the series is dated between 1920 and 1940.
  There is a manuscript of "Johnny's Song," written by Kurt Weill with a note dedicating the song to Crawford. The manuscript and accompanying note are housed separately from the series in an oversized box.
  - A Night of Love, 1925 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - A Room with a View, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 2)